# **Nick Korintus**

Media, PA 19063 (908) 472-8109 nicholas.korintus@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/nick-korintus github.com/npkorintus nickkorintus.com

### **Profile**

Front-end developer with experience in full stack development. Competent in all stages of the SDLC, including design, documentation, analysis, and testing. Natural problem solver and critical thinker. Highly motivated self-starter with a passion for learning new technologies and improving my craft.

### **Skills**

- HTML, CSS, JavaScript, TypeScript, React, Astro, Material-UI, Sass/SCSS/LESS, Bootstrap, AngularJS
- C#, .NET, Java, SQL, Liquibase, REST APIs, Swagger
- Git, Github/Bitbucket, Jenkins, Visual Studio, VS Code, NPM, Yarn, Vite, Postman, Swagger
- Agile methodologies (Scrum/Kanban), CI/CD, Jira/Trello
- Responsive web development, UI/UX design, software testing, project management

## **Experience**

Freelance Web Developer, Remote, November 2024 - Present

- Designed and developed custom websites focusing on clean, user-friendly interfaces and high performance using HTML, JavaScript, Astro, and CSS/LESS/SCSS
- Delivered end-to-end solutions, from initial concept and design to deployment and ongoing maintenance.
- Collaborated with clients to define project scope, user needs, and brand vision, resulting in websites that meet business objectives and drive user engagement.

#### Quivers, Remote, April 2022 - August 2023

**UI** Engineer

- Delivered new user interface views, features, and workflows for a new customer-facing SaaS platform using JavaScript, HTML, SCSS, and Bootstrap
- Implemented new features and enhancements to legacy platform using Angular, React, and SCSS
- Collaborated with a small team of in-house engineers and off-shore development team to deliver technically optimized features which offer a Grade A customer experience

#### Entech Consulting / Anovaa, Malvern, PA May 2020 – April 2022

Software Developer

- Developed new and improved existing user interfaces using React, CSS, and Material-UI
- Added new and improved existing functionality to REST APIs using C#, .NET, and MariaDB
- Collaborated with product owners to design and create friendly UI/UX for new features

#### Configuration Developer

- Created and deployed scripts for configuring new clients to a multi-tenant SaaS web application
- Designed and built a Membership Verification feature using React, C#/.NET, SQL, and Python
- Created and deployed client email and document templates using C#, ASP.NET Core, and Razor

#### Junior UI/.NET Developer

• Maintained and updated high-traffic websites and microsites for external clients using TeamSite CMS, HTML, CSS, C#, ASP.NET, and Microsoft SQL Server

- Created documentation highlighting best development practices and processes
- Provided training and mentoring to fellow development team members and external partners

#### Advisor Innovation Lab, Bryn Mawr, PA January 2019 – March 2020

Software Engineer Intern

- Designed and built a reusable tooltip component for UI component library using React, Typescript and SCSS
- Led a UI/UX redesign project for an enterprise administration application

## **Education**

Middlesex College, Edison, NJ

A.S. in Computer Science, 2018

Villanova University, Villanova, PA

B.A. in Italian Studies, 2009

## **Certifications**

JavaScript Algorithms and Data Structures, Free Code Camp (April 2020) Responsive Web Design, Free Code Camp (December 2019)